I'm driving.
I... You promised.
- Yeah.
- Love you.
Yeah, you do.
Nobody move!
The keys!
Give me the keys!
Step away from the car!
Get away from the car.
Come on, baby.
Go, baby, go!
Buckle up!
Hey!
Hey, stop!
HPD! Stop!
Get off me!
- Get Off me!
- Behind your back!
Dispatch 42!
- Female suspect in custody.
- Get off of me!
Like butter, baby!
Let's celebrate.
Where is she?
What happened?
It was on the scanner,
cops chased her down.
That's what happens
when you let a woman drive.
What are you smiling about?
Cole, I just...
Go get a chamois.
Come buff this out.
We should get out of town.
We can't get out of town.
We've still got product to move.
- We still need a car.
- What if she talks?
You don't know Marie.
"Armed robbery,
assault with a deadly weapon"
"resisting arrest, felony eluding,
reckless driving."
You know,
a cruel man would tack on
running through
a red light and speeding
but I'm not a cruel man.
FBI, huh?
Didn't know I, uh,
rated the Feds.
Your boyfriend, Cole Foster
runs a luxury-car-theft ring
with jobs from Phoenix to Tulsa.
Crossing state lines
makes it federal.
- How old are you, Marie?
- Who cares?
You have a lot of life left.
I know you don't want
to throw it away.
Under federal law
we can charge you with being
your boyfriend's co-conspirator.
You know what that means?
That means you answer for what
you did and anything he did.
And you can get
50 to 60 years, easy.
You don't wanna walk
out of prison at 80.
So help us, and we'll make
this mess go away a lot faster.
Tell us where Cole is.
You bastards.
I'd go to hell for Cole.
You think I care about jail?
Lock me up.
Take her.
- Plan B?
- Plan B.
Don't tell a whole lot
of little lies.
Just one big lie is enough
and everything else
just stays the same
you're from Chicago
you got three brothers
- you're ticklish.
- I am not ticklish.
- Yes, you are.
- Everybody is ticklish
when they're being tickled.
If you want someone to trust
you, ask them for a favor
- even a small one.
- Jane, I know what I'm doing.
One last thing.
When you shower,
promise me this
that you will wear
the flip-flops, please.
A, it makes you look less attractive
which should be considered
and B,
the floor is a Petri dish.
- Okay.
- I hear you.
- Thank you.
It's time.
Are you good?
Yeah.
The warden has set it up so that you
will be sharing a cell with Marie.
The sooner you get her to tell you
where Cole is, the better.
I'm ready.
Be careful, huh?
- I'll wait for you.
- Hush. Go!
"McGregor, Teresa.
Transfer from Amarillo"
"prisoner number 90026, correct?"
We don't tolerate gangs,
drugs, or violence.
You violate the rules
and you will be transferred
to a higher-security institution.
Keep to the straight and narrow,
and we'll all get along fine.
This is you.
Hey.
I'm Teresa McGregor.
I'm your new bunkmate.
- What are you in for?
- Burglary.
Judge wouldn't give bail
for repeat offenders
so here I am.
- You?
- Grand Theft Auto.
Well, that's what they're charging me with
and like a million other things.
McGregor.
- That's Irish, huh?
- My grandparents came over from Derry.
Marie Flanagan.
Uh, mine were from
somewhere like that.
I don't... I don't know.
Uh, you mind if I take the top bunk?
I get a little claustrophobic.
Well, that depends, are you crazy
enough to take it from me?
Forget it.
What I thought.
Whoa. Whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa.
What do you got there?
- Coffee. Why?
- That's Jane's cup.
- Seriously?
- Well, it's a rookie mistake no problem.
Just wash it, put it back
and he'll never know.
Well, he, he might not know.
- Okay. Sure.
- Yeah.
Hey, any idea who that is?
She was here
a few days ago.
Uh, her name's Cass,
I think.
Abbot said she's with the CIA.
Don't know what she's here for.
No, no, seriously, you...
- You wanna wash that.
- Okay.
- Your agent inside already?
- She's sharing a cell with Flanagan.
The plan is for Lisbon to get Marie
to give up Cole Foster's location.
I just hope
it doesn't take long.
I know it's risky.
The Agency appreciates everything
your people are doing.
Ms. Cass, I'm all about
interagency cooperation
it's great.
But thanks to you
I put one of my best people in danger
to catch a car thief
and I don't know why the CIA
cares so damn much.
Between us?
Sure.
Foster sells
the cars he steals overseas.
His buyers are in
the Middle East, Europe.
So he's plugged in
to international smugglers.
People who smuggle luxury cars
can smuggle other things
drugs, money, bombs.
So you think
he's tied to terrorists.
I think the people
he works with are
and if you can get him
into custody
we can have those names.
Why go after him now?
The NSA has picked up
some chatter
about plans for
an operation here in the U.S.
We think one of Foster's
contacts is in on it
and it's coming soon.
Now, I appreciate
that your agent is in danger
but I would think
that you would agree
it's worth the risk.
What's the CIA have to say?
Well, nothing worth repeating.
What's that?
It's a map Wylie made for me.
Uh, this is Marie's route
during her car chase.
You notice how she turns
that way, then that way
- then that way again?
- Huh. So?
Well, when you're being chased
your subconscious
wants you to run home
but your conscious mind
doesn't want to lead
your pursuers there.
So, she has, uh...
Zigzagged in a way.
But where she really wanted
to go was this neighborhood.
That makes sense,
industrial area.
Economic downturn hit it hard,
lots of empty warehouses.
Just the place to hide
a lot of stolen cars.
Well, if we find
Cole's base there
we might be able
to scoop him up.
Yeah, but that's
four square miles.
We need a little bit more
to go on.
Well, which warehouse
is it?
Well, I can't do everything.
Oh. Well, uh, let's see
if we can narrow it down.
You got it.
You're wearing a new aftershave.
I believe it has Ambergris in it.
That's very expensive
for the office.
What's the special occasion?
- You know, date night with the wife.
- Nice.
Yeah, Lena's on a short list
for a position
in the commerce department
in D.C. so we're celebrating.
Well, tell her congratulations for me.
Oh, well, it's not said
and done yet, but we're hopeful.
You know, Jane.
We will bring Lisbon
back home safe.
Of course we will.
Okay.
- "What's your problem?"
- "Yeah, I don't like you."
"I don't really care!"
"Excuse me.
I'm gonna use the phone."
"Yeah, you're gonna get in line
like the rest of us."
- "I was in line!"
- "Oh, really?"
"Yeah. You can't tell because you're
so busy looking at your own stupid..."
"Hey, watch it, watch it."
- "What, I wasn't even talking to you!"
- "Back off!"
"You think you're too good to stand
in line or something?"
You've been eyeballing me
since I walked through that door.
- What's going on?
- Yo, mind your business!
- Stay out of it.
- Hey.
Cut it out.
I'm not trying
to pick a fight.
Bitch, who the hell
are you?
Somebody who doesn't
want to get transferred
to higher security
just like you.
Oh, yeah?
We're gonna go back
to our bunk
and you're gonna get back
in line and make a phone call.
Hey. Phone's open.
I'm gonna call my old man.
Yeah. Whatever.
Oh, and I'll see you around.
- What the hell was that?
- I raised three brothers.
You learn to deal with aggression.
Well, I didn't need your help, all right?
I can handle myself.
How you holding up?
"Roommate troubles?"
It's like we're doing the cha-cha.
"I take one step forward,
she takes one step back."
Does she have any friends?
She likes picking fights
a little bit too much, a loner.
"Oh, well, she needs a friend."
We all do.
- You have not met this girl.
- Oh, a tough cookie
likes to hide her emotions
under a hard veneer?
Yeah.
Yeah, I think I've met
a woman like that before.
Is that so?
Uh, you, you wanna know how I got
her to lower her guard?
How?
Uh, I lowered my own.
Marie.
- Marie.
- What?
I can't sleep.
- You?
- No. It's too hot.
Yeah.
I miss my boyfriend.
What's he do?
He's a hustler.
He uses his brains
to get by.
Like a con artist?
That's cool.
How long you been together?
We've known each other
a long time, years and years
but we weren't together.
I mean, we,
we were friends, but...
I couldn't admit that my feelings
had changed for him
not even to myself.
I know what that's like.
I tried to run away.
I met a nice guy.
He was a good man
but not the right man.
I was gonna marry him.
Then Patrick told me
he loved me
and that he didn't
want me to leave.
- What'd you do?
- I stayed.
It felt so good
not to live a lie anymore.
Scary, too.
I don't know
what's gonna happen
you know, if he's gonna
stick around or...
My boyfriend,
his name's Cole.
He's a real outlaw.
I like that.
Cole and me, we live wild.
I mean, it's like wild.
Like, right now,
we're living in a warehouse.
You live in a warehouse?
It's actually more like a hideout.
Cars like
you wouldn't believe
million-dollar cars,
expensive stuff
but we live off of
gas station chimichangas. It's...
It's wild.
Wild is one thing,
no shower is another.
Aw, hell, we have a shower.
Cole even stole cable from
the no-tell motel down the block.
I hear we caught a break.
Yeah, Lisbon called in.
Marie told her about a warehouse
she and Cole stay in.
- Did she give a location?
- Not an address
but looking in the neighborhood
Jane pinpointed
we found a warehouse that fit
all the details Marie gave us
down to the
gas station chimichangas.
Chimichangas?
Yeah, well, that...
That's not important.
What is important
is that the warehouse
is leased by a fake corporation.
Sounds like
what we're looking for.
Well, it's enough for a warrant.
Why don't you get a team together
and head down there
and see what you can find?
That's a load of crap, man.
You got nothing on me.
You're gonna be hearing
from my lawyer.
We just caught you in a warehouse
full of stolen vehicles.
You're the one that should be trying
to make a deal with me.
If you're too stupid to see that
I don't know what value you have
for the FBI.
Uh, come on, man.
Let's... Let's talk.
Do you wanna tell me
where Cole Foster is?
Look, his old lady
got caught last week.
It has him paranoid as hell.
He's in town.
That's all I know.
If he's so paranoid,
why is he sticking around?
Good question.
Tell me
how I can find him.
Man, I don't even have
his burner number.
Hendricks is the only one that
knows how to get a hold of him.
Ronald Hendricks?
That's right.
"And how can I find Hendricks?"
"I don't know. He's with Cole I guess."
We already put a BOLO
out on Hendricks.
- That's a dead end.
- Maybe.
Marie's useless as a source
of information now.
Let's pull Lisbon out.
Marie may be useless
as a source of information
- but she still has a use.
- What's that?
Well, Cole should leave town,
but he won't.
It's obvious why,
he doesn't wanna leave Marie
- so, we give her to him.
- How?
We don't pull Lisbon
out of jail
we break her out.
- You wore a vest.
- Oh, this? This old thing?
Well, I thought
I should look the part.
I like it.
Well, that's... That's good to know.
How are you?
I'm fine. The food is not good.
I would kill for a salad.
So, we didn't get him?
What now?
You and Marie are gonna break out
of here and lead us to Cole.
Okay.
You're gonna provide
the breakout plan
Marie is gonna provide the ride.
And you think Cole's
gonna be waiting for her?
Maybe. Or he'll be very close.
How are we
gonna break out?
I'm working on a plan now.
So I just say, Marie, we're gonna
bust out of this joint?
It's not gonna be your idea,
it's gonna be her idea.
Cousin Ricky
needs surgery again.
He's got to lose
his gall bladder.
- Doctor says it's got to go.
- Huh?
Huh, what does it do?
What does a gall bladder do?
I mean, can you even live
without a gall bladder?
When she leaves that room
breaking out will be
the only thing on her mind.
Have a seat.
Bite me.
So, I guess that means
you haven't changed your mind
about telling us
where Cole Foster is.
Okay.
Well, he can send you a postcard
when you get settled.
What does that mean?
That means I'm allowing
the Houston D.A.
to file charges on you.
You will be transferred
to Mountain View
- while you await your trial.
- Mountain View?
That's a SuperMax.
Well, it takes about 48 hours
for the paperwork to clear
if you wanna get packed.
Uh, no way.
Mountain View's for crazies.
Well, it's a more
structured environment
23 hours a day in your cell
- constant supervision.
- You can't do that.
- You can't.
- I can!
So you enjoy your time here
for the next 48 hours
because it is the best
it's gonna get for a long time.
SuperMax.
I hear you don't even
get out of your cell to shower
they just roll one up
to the door.
I just... I won't go. I won't.
I won't, I won't, I won't go.
That does not sound good.
I got some bad news, too.
The D.A.'s going after me.
I'm a three-time loser.
I'm facing 25 to life.
I can't do it.
Damn pigs.
I'm so sick of getting
pushed around. It's...
I just wish there was
something we could do.
We... Just get out of here.
Like break out?
Yeah.
I guess. It's easier to get out of here
than Mountain View.
Hey.
You've done break-ins
before, right?
How hard can a breakout be?
Hard.
But that doesn't mean
it's impossible.
But you can figure it out, right?
You got brains. I can tell.
Maybe.
But if I get us on
the other side of that wall
someone's got to get us
out of state right away.
Otherwise, the cops
will just pick us up.
My man can get us
anywhere we wanna go.
Where do you wanna be?
Patrick's in Florida.
I could go see him.
I'm not gonna rot
in a SuperMax.
I say we do it.
I'm in.
I'm gonna make a phone call.
I knew I liked you.
No. Listen. No, Mark,
listen to me for a second.
Will you listen?
I swear you have nothing
between your ears but wax.
You're my brother
and I love you
but you are dumber
than a sack of rocks.
"Now, will you just calm down
and listen for a minute?"
This one's angry
at her brother.
- It's not Marie.
- She's call before lights-out.
New call.
She wants to know
who's feeding Taco, her cat.
I hope someone is.
Don't we need warrants
to listen on phone calls?
Not for jailhouse payphones.
Her son is feeding Taco.
Taco is being fed.
Good. New call.
It's not Marie.
You know, I used to date
a prisoner.
- No, you didn't.
- Her name was Velma.
Big Vel.
- Big Vel?
- Mm-hm. Yep.
And why did Big Vel
go to prison?
Horse thief.
Yeah, right.
Well, I...
- Wait, hold on. New call.
- "Hey."
- I think it's her.
- "It's Marie."
- Let me listen.
- "I got some news, big news."
"The kids are coming home
from camp tomorrow."
You need to pick up the kids
a little sooner than expected.
"Right. I got it."
- Is that Cole?
- I don't know.
"When should I pick them up?"
I'll be in touch again soon.
"Be ready."
Can we trace the call?
No, she called a burner.
No chance of tracking him down
from that.
But now he'll come to us.
It's time to plan a jailbreak.
These are cameras.
These are where
we'll find the COs.
I've got maps of electric lines,
pipes, guard schedules.
Well, the problem is simple.
Lisbon and Marie
are inside the wall
we need to get them
outside the wall.
There's three ways
to get past a wall
over, under, and through.
Well, they don't
have time to tunnel.
Sewage lines, if they can get
to the main drainage area?
They'll need tools
to open it up.
Can they go over the wall?
What about the guard towers?
See the southwest corner there?
Visibility's low.
I mean, that section of wall
is 30 feet.
- Grappling hooks?
Seems to me
they should just go through.
I mean, the people
that built this jail
were nice enough
to put doors in the walls.
Why don't they just use them?
You see, there, that... That door.
They should go
right through that door.
They're gonna need a mop
and a bucket with a hole in it.
"Okay, so they'll look
like they're cleaning."
- "Why does the bucket need a hole?"
- "We'll get there."
This door here is the key, not as
an escape route. It's a misdirect.
"This is the boundary between
the guards' world and the prisoners'."
"At shift change, it should be
empty except for the guard."
"When the bucket empties,
it'll start a chain reaction."
"A noisy one."
If they're spotted in prison clothes
on that side of the line, game's over.
Which is why they have to head
straight to the employees' locker room.
And if they get there
just before shift change
"they can leave with the cafeteria workers."
What if someone thinks
they don't belong?
The key to walking
in or out of any place
is posture and momentum.
"You just keep moving forward"
"like you know exactly
where you're going."
"People see
that kind of posture"
"and they decide
that you belong there"
"before their conscious brain
can even think about it."
Then she's in your hands.
That's Hendricks over there.
He'll get us to Cole,
and Cole will take us out of state.
Hey, there.
- This your friend?
- Teresa, it's Hendricks.
- Hey, Teresa.
- You keep your paws off her. She's taken.
We're in position.
We have eyes on the car.
Vega, Lisbon's car
has just pulled out.
Not too close.
"Cole is not inside.
Do you see them?"
Don't worry.
The chopper's got them.
I thought Cole would've picked
them up himself.
No, he's thinking like a hunted
animal right now, he's hiding.
"Hold on.
They're slowing down."
"Not sure what they're doing."
"Vega, be alert."
We've just pulled into
a parking garage off Sunshine.
The chopper can't see in here.
We're gonna lose her.
Abbot, what is going on?
They're switching cars.
I'm gonna go follow her.
Watch the exit.
Hey. You wanna go your own way,
that's up to you.
I need a ride out of Texas.
That was the deal. Let's go.
They switched vehicles.
There's no sign of Lisbon.
Cho and I will traverse
the north and south streets
a one-mile radius.
"We'll get other teams
to help us search."
You don't even know
what kind of car she's driving.
How far is the garage?
- Uh, from here, three miles.
- All right.
They have to meet Cole someplace.
That gives us a little time.
Let's go.
We're gonna join the search.
Cole told me
to call from here.
He'll let me know
where to meet him.
Tell him to hurry up.
- You hungry?
- Sure.
Yeah, I'm starving.
Let's get something to eat.
What?
We just got out of jail.
Oh, right.
Hey.
I'm gonna get
a big pile of cookies
and candy
and a soda big enough
to drown in.
- What do you want?
- I think I'm just gonna get some water.
Oh, look at this, chocolate.
That could be good.
- These are...
- Hey!
Hey, troublemaker.
What are you doing?
- What, is this your new BFF?
- Yes, this is Teresa McGregor.
Teresa McGregor,
meet Cole.
Teresa McGregor? I don't know her.
Why'd you bring her here?
'Cause I promised her
a ride out of here.
I didn't promise
Teresa McGregor a ride.
Uh, this isn't charity.
The breakout plan
was my idea.
Come on, Cole!
She's good people, seriously.
All right, good people.
How do you feel about
getting out of Texas?
- Sounds good to me.
- All right.
Half a mile down that road
there's a helicopter
- all fueled up, all right?
- Yeah?
It'll get us past any dragnet
they got set up for you
the two of you troublemakers.
Wow. A helicopter? Since when
do you fly a helicopter?
Hendricks flew them
in Afghanistan.
Don't worry
your pretty little head.
You two buy whatever you need to buy.
Let's get out of here.
- I'm getting the sixer. Let's go.
- I'm just gonna grab some aspirin.
- I have a headache.
- Okay.
Hey.
What are you typing
on that phone, man?
- Excuse me?
- Let me check out your phone.
Let me see your phone?
What are you hiding?
Hey, man! What are you, crazy?
Back off!
Do you want me to call the cops?
Hey...
Come here.
Did you just see him
flop like that?
Come here.
Come over!
- You got a problem?
- No, I told you she's cool.
No. No problem.
All right, let's go!
Let's go, let's go, good people! Come on!
Out of here!
I need you two
to stay where you are.
- This is a crime scene.
- Michelle Vega, FBI.
We heard the shots fired call
over the scanner.
We have reason to believe this could
be connected to a missing agent.
- I need your assistance.
- Yes, ma'am.
How long have you been
on the scene?
Call came in
15 minutes ago.
I've been here about a minute.
You guys got here fast.
Get crime-scene tape up.
Have any other responding
officers set up the perimeter.
And check to see
if the security cameras
- caught the crime on tape.
- Yes, ma'am.
That's her.
That's Lisbon's footprint.
So she's still with him.
That... that's good, right?
Look at the angle her foot is.
It's like she's pointing.
She's, she's pointing us
that direction.
Or she stepped in it by accident.
No, she would never do that.
Let's... Let's go.
Okay, Jane, we don't know where they are.
There's protocol here.
I'll call Abbott, explain the situation
see if he and Cho are close.
You call whoever
you need to call, yeah.
- Let's take this one step at a time, okay?
- Absolutely.
Abbott.
Let's get in the air, yeah?
Uh, I just need a couple more minutes.
Let me check one more last thing.
When are you meeting up
with your man?
I'm gonna call him
as soon as we get out of state.
Love you, baby.
Hey, there, Missy.
- What were you doing?
- Nothing.
Hendricks, grab your gun.
What's your game?
What do you need a gun for?
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
Is that right?
- "Where'd she come from anyway?"
- "She was my celly. I told you."
- "So why's she need a gun?"
- "How should I know?"
I don't like this.
- I do not like this.
- Baby.
"Don't baby me."
"She was going for the gun.
She thinks she's slick."
"She thinks she's gonna
put one over on us."
"So, what are we gonna do?"
"What? You want me to draw you a
sketch? You know what."
"Just let me think
a second, okay?"
"This isn't the time for thinking.
It's time for action."
Hey. We're ready to go.
Not until we deal with her.
Sure as hell can't leave her behind.
She knows what our plans are.
Look, that only leaves
one option.
She's good people.
Just make it quick.
"Excuse me."
Patrick Jane, FBI.
Drop your weapons. You're coming with me.
Got this place
surrounded with snipers.
You put your guns down right now, you walk
out of here alive. You hear that?
- You're lying.
- Oh, really?
You think I'd walk in here
unarmed with no cover, do you?
Well, I know you
from somewhere.
Cole, there's a sniper in that tree
over there. I can see his glass.
No one has to die, not today.
I know you.
What's he doing here?
- Who is he?
- It's her boyfriend!
I saw him at the jail.
He's a con artist.
It's some kind of trick.
What the hell's going on?
Well, here we are.
You walked out here
to face us by yourself
with nothing but a rearview
mirror for a backup?
Worth a shot.
Sorry, I, I couldn't
think of anything else.
It's okay.
- "FBI!"
- Drop your weapon right now!
- Don't move.
- Put your gun down.
- Freeze.
- Get down.
Get on your knees!
Put your hands on your hand!
- Hands where I can see them!
- Do it now!
- That's an order! Now!
- Cuff her, Vega.
- Okay. Okay.
- Yes, sir.
Oh, I'm so glad
you decided to catch up.
- You dropped this.
- Thank you.
- Hey.
Here we are.
I know what you want.
You want my contacts.
International smugglers.
I can give them to you.
Lots of them.
Names, locations.
Hell, I will tell you
what their favorite foods are.
But first,
what are you gonna give me?
You give us everything
and we don't charge Marie
as an accessory
to the murder you committed.
She'll get out, have a chance
to have some kind of life.
You kidding me?
You think that I'm gonna spend the
only coin I got on that crazy bitch?
You're gonna have to do
something for me.
You killed a man today for
no reason at all
you did it on tape and you did it
in front of an FBI agent.
No death penalty,
that's the deal.
Now, you're gonna die in jail
just not gonna be for a while is all.
Take it or leave it.
I'll take it.
Yes. We can work with this.
- "Read through this, please."
- We'll send you a transcript
as soon as he's done signing.
Agent Cho,
did he agree to talk?
Yeah. You did good today.
Agent Cho, sir,
may I say something?
You don't have to call me
sir or agent.
I've been observing your work
and I admire the way
you carry yourself on the job.
This place is a little bit crazy
but you make sense to me.
Okay.
I would welcome the opportunity
to work with you more
learn how you do things,
get some pointers.
I don't know.
I'll have to think about it.
Oh. Oh, okay. Sounds good.
Thank you.
- Jane.
- Yeah?
Just talked to Abbott. The CIA got in
touch with him about one of the names
that Cole gave up,
some smuggler.
Oh, that's great.
That's progress.
Well, the Agency squeezed Cole
for everything they could get
associates, habits,
personal life.
Well, what does that
got to do with us?
Turns out we know
the smuggler's girlfriend.
- Well, you do.
- I do?